In Kyoto, there is a secret society
.that has existed since the Taishou era.
京都には大正時代から続くという秘密結社がある
There are always seven seats,
その座席は常に七つと定められ
and the humans who occupy them each take
.on the name of one of the Seven Lucky Gods.
各座を占める人間たちはそれぞれ
七福神の名をもって呼ばれた
They are our natural enemies, those who
.paralyze children with fear: the Friday Fellows.
泣く子も黙る狸の天敵
“金曜倶楽部”とは 彼らのことだ
And why are they our
natural enemies, you ask?
何故我らの天敵であるか
Because they stew and eat a tanuki
.at their year-end bash.
彼らは忘年会に狸鍋を喰うからである
Though our daily life may be tranquil,
安寧と続く日々の中に
their stew is a regularly scheduled
.nightmare we have once a year.
一年に一度立ち現れる定期的悪夢
Even our father, the great
.Shimogamo Souichirou,
我が偉大なる父 下鴨総一郎も
met his end all too soon
.in the Friday Fellows' stew.
金曜倶楽部の鍋として
その生涯をあっけなく閉じた
Thus we are reminded
かくして我らは思い出す
that humans are the ones who
.are on top of the food chain.
喰う者の頂点に立つのは
人間であると
面白くない世の中
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
Original     Work
Morimi Tomihiko
"Uchouten Kazoku"
Gentousha Publishing
面白くすればいいさ
omoshiroku sureba ii sa
this dull world more interesting
“つまらねえ”のが口癖なのは
tsumaranee no ga kuchiguse nano wa
Some people love to claim that something is boring
それこそホントにつまらない
sore koso honto ni tsumaranai
That habit is the most boring thing of all
文句を言うのは簡単だけど
monku wo iu no wa kantan dakedo
It's easy to complain about stuff
誰かは何もくれない
dareka wa nannmo kurenai
but it doesn't do any good at all
走らないけど止まりはしない
hashiranai kedo tomari wa shinai
That sort of useless waste of time
dare ni mo nagareru ahou no chi
runs in our idiot blood
誰にも流れる阿呆の血
sawageba sawagu hodo kakitateru
Just party on and on, and the more you do
騒げば騒ぐ程かき立てる
なんと素晴らしき日々
nanto subarashiki hibi
the more awesome will be your days
omoshiroku nai yo no naka
You just have to make
面白くない世の中
omoshiroku sureba ii no sa
this dull world more interesting
面白くすればいいのさ
jibun de mitsukerya
The things you find for yourself in this world
自分で見つけりゃ
hodohodo ni paradaisu da
quickly turn it into a little paradise
ほどほどにパラダイスだ
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
Before you know it,
気がつけば何時だって
ki ga tsukeba itsu datte
Before you know it,
有頂天人生だ
uchouten jinsei da
you live a life of pure ecstasy
Episode Five
The Friday Fellows
So, you're still alive.
生きてたかよ
Wouldn't be here otherwise.
ご覧の通り
Still on the run, by the looks of it?
その様子じゃまだ逃亡中か
I'm helping out at a secondhand camera
.shop in Osaka's Nipponbashi district.
大阪の日本橋で中古カメラ屋を手伝ってる
Are you going to be okay?
大丈夫か？
Benten likes to hang out in Osaka too.
弁天様は大阪にだって遊びに行っておられるぞ
Just don't tell her about me.
告げ口するなよ？
Think I can promise that?
保障できるか
Whenever I'm threatened, I tend to
babble things I don't mean to—
脅されたら己の意思に反してぺらぺら喋っちまうんだ
かあ
か
か かあ
すう す す すす すう はあ
Is she gone?
行ったか
Yeah.
行った
お おおおお
はあ
There really is something
.irresistible about this thrill.
このスリルがたまらなくもある
Well then.
では
は
あ
うふふ
ん
So, about this whole Benten affair.
弁天様のことなんだけどね
Yaichirou went to ask
.Master Akadama to intercede,
矢一郎が赤玉先生にとりなしてくれるように
頼みに行ったけれど
but he came back fuming,
ぷりぷりして戻ってきたわ
saying, "I'm through with bowing
my head to Master!"
俺はもう先生に頭を下げるのは嫌だって
He was bristling mad!
毛を逆立てて怒るのだもの
He needs to learn a bit of tolerance.
あの子ももう少し器を大きくしなくちゃいけないねえ
Well, maybe it's already water under the bridge,
兄上の力を借りずとも
案外会ってみたら一切が
水に流されているかもしれない
and I won't need my brother's help at all.
Maybe so. Benten might be dangerous,
確かに 弁天さんという人は恐ろしい人だけれども
but she's fickle and capricious, after all.
気まぐれで飽きっぽいからね
But what'll you do if it's not
water under the bridge?
でも流されてなかったらどうするの？
うーん
I like you so much I could just eat you up.
食べちゃいたいほど好きなのだもの
はあ
Ugh, humans are even nastier than tengu.
全く 人間というものは天狗よりも質が悪い
But you know, most of them are good people.
でもね まあ大方は良い人だよ
You can say that because
.you owe your life to one.
母上には命の恩人があるからな
It's also thanks to Mr. Yodogawa that you
.were brought into this world, you know.
あなたがこうして世に生を受けたのも
淀川さんのおかげなのだからね
I still remember the taste of the
.rice balls he gave me that night.
あの時いただいたおにぎりの味は
今も忘れられない
We need to be thankful.
感謝しなくちゃいけないよ
Mamiana Antiques
ん？
はあ
ん ん
Man, I demolished that.
はあ
食った食った
You sure do eat like a pig.
意地汚い食い方だな
あ？
海星か？
Kaisei?
Why are you in that dresser?
なんでそんな箪笥に入っている？
Shut up! Who cares?
うるせえよ 放っとけ
So, what's been happening?
で どうだ？　最近は
Is Yajirou doing okay?
矢二郎兄さんは元気か？
Yeah, he's doing fine at the bottom of his well,
ああ
井戸の底で元気にしてるよ
listening to people's troubles and such.
身の上相談もやってるし
I... like Yajirou.
矢二郎さんは私 好き
I go to talk to him sometimes, too.
時々相談にも行く
There's a rumor that Benten visits him as well.
弁天もあそこには顔を出すという噂だけどね
What kind of worries could the peerless Benten have?
天下無敵の弁天様にどんな悩みがあると言うんだ？
How would I know?
知るもんですか
Maybe she can't decide which tanuki to eat at the end of the year.
どうせ次の忘年会でどの狸を喰うか
悩んでるんじゃないの？
There's a rumor that you're headed for the stew pot this time.
今年はあんたが鍋にされるって噂だけど
That so?
どうなの？
Not if I can help it.
そんな予定は無い
This is all because a mere tanuki like you
got involved with that wannabe tengu!
狸の分際であんな生天狗と関わり合いになるから
Go back to Osaka as soon as you can.
早めに大阪へ帰りなさいよ
If you hang around here for too long,
you'll end up in that stew pot for real.
あんまりうろうろしてたら本当に喰われちゃうよ
That is a risk we all face as tanuki.
狸として生きる以上 鍋になることもあろう
When the time comes, I'm ready to plunge
.into that pot with a smile on my face.
その時は笑って鍋になってやる覚悟だ
You sure talk big for a guy with no balls.
強がり言うな
玉無しの癖に
ぶーっ
Just in case I get caught,
俺が捕まると困るから
I'd like you to hang onto this for me.
これを預かってくれ
What is it? A keepsake?
何よ 形見？
Tengu cigars.
天狗タバコだ
Please take them to Master Akadama for me.
赤玉先生に届けてくれ
I asked Yashirou to take care of him in my absence,
京都を離れている間
矢四郎に世話役を任せたが
but I hear Master's been making all kinds of unreasonable demands.
先生があれこれ無理難題を言って
困らせているらしい
A cigar in his mouth should shut him up.
先生を黙らせるには
その口に天狗タバコを突っ込むのがよろしい
ダメだわ 見えない
No good. I can't see it.
How could you see anything in there?
そんなふうに箪笥の中にいるからだ
Just come out already.
いい加減に出てこい
No way. I refuse.
嫌 お断り
I don't get it.
意味が分からん
What's the point?
どうしろって言うんだ
To our honored guest on the second floor,
お二階のお客様
Benten has arrived.
弁天様のご来店でございます
う
ん
はっ
んんっ
はあ
んっ
ううう
う
はあ
あ
あっ
Is that Yasaburou character here?
その矢三郎とやらはここにおりますか
Well, they do call him
"Yasaburou the Fugitive,"
逃げの矢三郎と言われるくらいだもの
so I suspect he may have already run away.
逃げた後かもしれないわね
What would you like to do?
ではどうされます？
I can take you to the Friday Fellows.
金曜倶楽部までお送りしますよ
I'm a little tired.
少し疲れたわ
I'll rest here for a bit.
ここで一休みします
Hey, Teikinbou.
ねえ帝金坊
There are two daruma dolls here.
ここに二つの達磨があるのだけれど
Isn't that strange?
妙ちくりんではありませんか？
The burn marks, dirt, and other
.scuff marks are exactly identical.
どちらも同じ所が焼け焦げて
汚れ方がそっくり同じでしょう？
I see.
なるほど
That certainly is mysterious.
確かに面妖ですな
Yasaburou has always been
.good at shape-shifting.
矢三郎は化けるのがとても上手な子でしたよ
ふう
ぐふ ごほ ごほ
Long time no see, Yasaburou.
お久しぶりね 矢三郎
How'd you know I was here?
何故私がここにいると分かりました？
Kinkaku and Ginkaku came to me for advice.
金閣と銀閣から相談を受けたのです
Apparently, their little sister had been
.going out alone from time to time.
最近 妹が時々一人で出掛けている
They suspected she might have gotten
.sweet-talked by some nasty male tanuki.
どうやら質の悪い雄狸にたぶらかされているらしいと
Those two are always meddling
.in the most troublesome ways.
本当にもう
どこまでもいらぬことばかりする奴らだ
They take such good care of their little sister.
妹思いの兄さんたちね
You're cute when you're round,
丸くて可愛いから
so you can stay as a daruma for a bit.
しばらく達磨のままでいらっしゃい
いずこへ？
Where are we going?
Not only did you wreck my inner parlor,
あなたは私の奥座敷を粉々にした上に
大切な扇を無くしたのですから
but you also lost my beloved fan.
You promised you'd entertain
the Friday Fellows, did you not?
金曜倶楽部で芸をする約束でしょう？
I won't take "I forgot" for an answer.
忘れたとは言わせないわ
There are no words that can express my regret
.for what happened during the Fire Festival.
大文字の件についてはお詫びの言葉もございません
But—
しかしながらあれは
I don't need apologies.
お詫びなんて結構よ
If we don't enjoy your performance,
we'll eat you, and that will be that.
芸の評判が悪ければ
あなたを鍋にすれば良いだけの話
Do you like beef sukiyaki?
すき焼きはお好き？
I have no beef with any food.
Except tanuki stew.
狸鍋でさえなければこの世に不味いものはありません
Personally, I find tanuki stew
.to be far better than sukiyaki.
私はすき焼きよりも狸鍋が好きよ
How befuddling.
物好きな
Beef is much tastier.
牛肉の方がどれだけ旨いか分からない
Your father ended up in a stew pot.
あなたのお父さんは鍋になったのよ
I wonder how many years it's been since then.
あれから何年になるかしら
You say that like you weren't
.sitting there eating it.
あなたも一緒に鍋を囲んだくせに
他人事のように言う
That was right after I was welcomed
.into the Friday Fellows.
私が金曜倶楽部に迎えられたばかりの頃でした
It was the first time I had ever eaten tanuki.
狸を食べたのは初めてだったわ
A truly delicious stew.
とても美味しいお鍋でしたよ
あ
ん？
Professor!
先生
Hey.
やあ
Here's our entertainment for the evening.
今宵の余興を務めてもらいます
I'm Shimogamo Yasaburou.
下鴨矢三郎と申します
Juroujin and Fukurokuju will be absent.
寿老人と福禄寿が欠席ということだ
I let the restaurant know in advance.
店には僕が言っておいたから
Well then, since all of today's attendees
are here, shall we begin?
では 今日のメンバーは揃ったということで
始めますかな
うん この音と匂いだけで
十分にビールが飲めますな
The sound and smell are more than enough
.to put me in a beer-drinking mood.
Then you can just stick to drinking beer, Ebisu.
ほう では恵比寿さんはビールだけ飲むがよい
I'll help myself to your share of the food.
あなたの取り分は私が
No, no. Appetizers have no meaning
.unless there's a main course.
いやいや 真打ちあってこその前座ですからね
Tasty meat is poison for your body.
旨い肉は体に毒だよ？
The guy who's smiling and laughing
.over there is Ebisu.
あちらでニコニコ笑ってらっしゃるのが恵比寿さん
The big one is Bishamon.
体の大きな人が毘沙門さん
Ebisu works in upper management
.at a bank in Osaka.
恵比寿さんは大阪の銀行の偉い人で…
Bishamon is the president
.of the Sengyoukaku Hotel.
毘沙門さんはホテル 千曉閣の社長さん
An intellectual once said,
とある軍人が言っておりますよ？
"Cows eat straw, so this isn't
beef stew, but straw stew."
牛は藁を食うのだから これは
牛鍋ではなく 藁鍋だと
And there's no cholesterol in straw, right?
Daikoku is the young proprietor of the
Kyoto-style restaurant "Chitose-ya."
大黒さんは京料理の千歳屋の若主人
Wouldn't you agree, Professor?
ああ 無いですよね 先生
I wonder if cows these days even eat straw.
今どきの牛は藁なんか食うのかいな
ずる
Hotei is a university professor.
布袋さんは大学の先生です
Cows these days drink beer while listening to Mozart.
There are two others, but they're absent today.
あと二人いらっしゃるけれども 今日は欠席
I wanted to see Juroujin, too.
So that means we're eating beer while drinking beer?
寿老人 お会いしたかったわ
What kind of person is Juroujin?
That's like eating rice with a side of rice.
寿老人って どんな人です？
He's a shark.
彼はアイスだね
A shark?
アイス？
You mean like a card shark?
かき氷屋さんですか
A loan shark.
高利貸しだね
ん
あーむ
き
ほいほいほいほいほい
はいはいはいはい
ほいほいほいほい
はいはいはい はいはい
ほいほい
はいはいはい
ほいほいほいほい ほい
We're lucky Hotei is at
.the other pot today.
今日は布袋さんがそちらの鍋で助かった
He doesn't care if the
.meat's not cooked at all,
布袋さんは生でも平気だから
うかうかしてるとこちらは食えないですからな
so if you're not paying attention,
you won't get to eat.
Seriously.
いや 全く
ほい
はい　くう
What do you say?
どう思うね君
Those three don't seem to be taking this seriously,
sitting there without a care in the world.
あちらは和平の上にあぐらをかいて
真剣味に欠けてはないか
Quite so.
誠に然り
Let's teach them the harshness of reality!
現実の厳しさを連中に教えてくれる
おお
It's about time we headed into the
.entertainment portion of the evening.
では そろそろ余興に参りましょう
よ 待ってました
We've been waiting!
That idiot.
あの阿呆め
Nishizaki Genemon's shop
Sukiyaki
restaurant
Teramachi
shopping district
ではこれより 下鴨家に古くから伝わりまする
And now, presenting the secret ceremony passed
down in the Shimogamo family since long ago:
秘技 くるくるぽんぽん七変化をご覧にいれまする
Bang, Bang! The Seven
Rapid-Fire Transformations!
Shall we begin?
ではいざ
はっ
Here we go!
おお
And again!
ほい
We're just getting started!
まだまだ
One more!
もういっちょ
おお
And even this!
これでもか
お おお
ああ
うっふん
Keep going, keep going!
続けて続けて
あんまり調子に乗っていたら
If you get too carried away,
you'll get devoured.
喰ってしまうわよ
は
Thank you very much.
お粗末様でした
Bravo!
いや ブラボー ブラボー
すげえもんだ さすが弁天さんのお客だ
Amazing! I'd expect nothing less
.from a guest of Benten's.
I have no idea what the trick could be.
いや 全く種が分かりませんな
おい 君はひょっとして狸じゃないのか？
Are you, by any chance, a tanuki?
あははは そうです 狸でございます
That's right. I'm a tanuki.
そうなのですよ
Indeed he is.
He's a tanuki I know.
この子は知り合いの狸です
Doesn't he look tasty?
美味しそうでしょう？
No, it would be a waste to eat
.someone with so much talent.
いやあ 喰うにはもったいない才能だ
いや これは喰えない
I just couldn't!
I've taken a real liking to you!
気に入った すごいもんだ
You're fantastic!
And so interesting!
おもちろい
ん あ
Come again next time!
次回もおいで
ほら 食べなさい
Here, please eat.
Eat as much as you want!
どんどん食べなさい
I guess I can let you off the hook for one night.
ま 今夜のところは許してあげましょう
You mean you won't cook me in a stew?
私を鍋にしないということですか
明日になったら分からないですけれどもね
Well, I can't say the same about tomorrow.
ん？
ふふ
Next month's year-end bash is tanuki stew, huh?
来月の忘年会は狸鍋だな
We'll borrow Chitose-ya as usual.
やはり例年通り千歳屋さんをお借りして
Of course. My doors are always open to you.
もちろんうちで結構ですよ
I doubt there are other restaurants
.that'd let you make tanuki stew.
他の料亭で狸鍋を作るわけにはいかんでしょう
はあ それにしても何故
忘年会には狸鍋と決まってんのかね
Why is it that we have to eat
tanuki every year, anyway?
I prefer beef.
俺は牛肉の方がいいのう
If you keep saying things like that,
you'll be expelled from the club.
そんなこと言ったら除名ですよ
It's a rule, that's why.
会則があるのだから
Wasn't it Tanizaki Jun'ichirou
who made that rule?
谷崎潤一郎が決めたのではなかったんですか
いや それ本当かね
Is that true?
寿老人から谷崎潤一郎も会員だったと聞きました
I heard from Juroujin that Tanizaki
.Jun'ichirou was once a member.
まあ 嘘くせえな
I find that hard to believe.
Would Tanizaki eat tanuki, though?
谷崎が狸なんぞ喰うかな
あの人ならば鱧ではないですか？
Wasn't he into eel?
But eel's a summer food.
いやしかし 鱧は夏のものですからね
The next one who has to bring
a tanuki is Hotei, right?
ああ 次は布袋さんが狸を連れてくるんだろう？
Hotei, you like tanuki, don't you?
布袋さんは狸がお好きなのですよね
ん？
んん 狸はかわゆいな
Tanuki are cute, aren't they?
.They sure are cute.
実にかわゆいんだ
They're all short and stout.
Isn't it charming?
あのずんぐりむっくりした格好に愛嬌があるでしょう
あ
Not to mention the way their
.eyes look at you blankly,
それにこっちをきょとんと見ている目とか
ちまちま走っていくお尻とかね
the way their butts wiggle as
...they timidly scurry away...
I see.
はあ
It was many years ago when I fell
.head over heels for tanuki.
僕が心底狸に惚れたのは
もう何年も前になるけれども
She was such a cute little thing.
あの狸は本当に可愛い奴だった
一人で北白川を歩いていた時ですよ
It happened when I was walking
.alone in Kitashirakawa.
あ
は
You poor thing. Are you hurt?
可哀想に 怪我をしたのか
Okay, c'mere.
さ おいで
Maybe she was just in
.pain from her injured leg,
怪我をした足が痛いのか
but she didn't struggle or make a fuss when
.I picked her up and took her to my place.
うちまで抱いて帰っても暴れもしないんだな
Then I dressed her wound
.and made some rice balls.
それで手当てをして握り飯をやって
That tanuki would gobble up anything.
She really loved to eat.
その狸がまた何でもむしゃむしゃ食うんだ
食いしん坊なんだ
Just like me!
僕とそっくり
雷がなるたびにひどく怖がってね
She was terribly scared
.whenever it thundered.
Huh?
え？
She was scared of... thunder?
雷を怖がる？
Sure was.
そうなんだ
She would run around whimpering, the poor thing.
鼻を鳴らして暴れるもんだから可哀想で
On nights when it thundered, I covered her with
.a blanket and stayed with her the whole time.
雷の鳴る夜は毛布を掛けてやって
ずっと一緒にいてやったもんです
ん
ああ
She got better, so I took her
.back to the mountains,
元気になったから山へ返してやったが
but as she was leaving, she
looked me right in the eyes!
これがまた山へ帰る時には僕の顔を見るんだ
She kept looking back as she walked away.
振り返り振り返り行くんですよ
あ？
Ah, Bishamon, you don't believe me, do you?
んん
毘沙門さんは信じてないでしょう
んん　ふんっ
But you weren't there, were you?
見てないからな
You didn't see how cute she was!
あなたはあの子の可愛さを見てないもの
She understood that I'd done
.her a favor by saving her.
あの子はね
Uh huh.
救われた恩を分かっておるんですよ
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
へいへいへい
賢いんだ
They're clever, tanuki are.
Sure, sure. Yep.
へいへい
狸は
へい
Ever since then, I've been
.in love with tanuki.
それ以来ですよ
僕が狸に惚れ込んだのは
あ いやだから不思議なんだよ
That's why it's so weird!
Hotei, we all know you
.have a thing for tanuki.
布袋さんがね うん 狸に惚れているというのは
ほら 皆 知ってる
But don't you happily scarf down
tanuki stew every year?
しかし あんた毎年狸鍋を
嬉しそうに喰ってんじゃないか
Isn't that kinda messed up?
おかしいじゃないか
Liking tanuki and eating tanuki
.are not contradictory.
狸が好きだということと 喰うということは矛盾しない
あなたのように渋々喰っていたんではしょうがないが
There will always be guys like
.you who eat it reluctantly,
but I'm always happy to.
僕はいつも喜んで喰う
Eating it and thinking how delicious it is
.is the least bit of courtesy you can show.
うまいうまいと喰うてやるのが礼儀というものです
あ いや しかしね
But hold on.
わざわざ好んで狸を喰う必要は無いじゃない？
You don't need to go out of your
way to eat tanuki, do you?
There are so many other
.tasty things in the world.
ああ 他にもいろいろ美味しいものがあるんだから
Well, I like them so much
.I could just eat them up.
食べちゃいたいほど好きなのだ
僕は
ああ 布袋さんとは長い付き合いだけれども
I've known you for a long time, Hotei,
but I still don't understand you.
やはり俺にはあんたという人が分からない
But I want you to understand!
分かって欲しいなあ
It's love!
愛ですよ愛
You get it, right?
分かるでしょう？
Not at all!
-ああ
-分からん
それが分からん
And I don't understand how you can't.
You know, tanuki are cute,
でもね 狸も可愛いけれども
同じくらい可愛い人がここにいる
but there's someone here
who is just as cute as them!
ああ こりゃダメだ
This is no good.
Hotei's wasted again.
布袋さんまた酔いつぶれた
I know how you feel,
but control yourself!
気持ちは分かるが抑えろ
Impossible!
Hey. This is getting kind of boring.
ねえ
私何だか退屈になってしまったわ
水飲みなさい
Let's go outside.
外へ行きましょう？
暴れないで
ああー
あ
Hey, Benten!
おーい 弁天さーん
Come back!
戻っておいでー
There's a huge moon out!
大きな月が出ているわね
I like round things.
丸いものが好きよ 私
そうですかい
Is that so?
I want the moon for myself.
お月様が欲しいな
Hey, why don't you go
fetch it for me, Yasaburou?
ほら
取ってきてごらん
矢三郎
I'd love to do you a favor,
but that's asking way too much.
そんな無茶な
いくら弁天様の頼みでも
Yeah, you're a good-for-nothing.
能無しなのね
Can't do anything at all.
何にもできないのだから
You're such a pitiful tanuki.
あなたはとても可哀想な狸ね
Call me whatever you want.
何とでも言ってくださいまし
When the moon is this pretty,
月が綺麗だと
I get kind of sad.
何だか悲しくなっちまうのよ
私は
You're just drunk.
酔ってるんですよ
Hardly. It'd take more than this.
酔ってないわよ
あれしきのことで
What are you so upset about?
何をそんなに切ながっているんです？
私に食べられるあなたが可哀想なの
You, my dear. Because you're
.going to be eaten by me.
喰わなければ良いのではないですか
But couldn't you just not eat me?
At some point, I'm definitely
.going to eat you up.
でも いつかきっと私はあなたを食べてしまうわ
I have issues with the fact that you can
.say "I'll eat you up" so casually.
食べてしまうわとあっさり言われても困ります
It's a matter of life or death for me, you know.
こちらも命に関わる問題だ
I just like you so much I could eat you up.
食べちゃいたいほど好きなのだもの
But if you eat the thing you like,
でも好きなものを食べたら
そうしたら好きなものが無くなってしまうんだもの
then it'll be gone!
Obviously! You can't have
.your tanuki and eat it too.
当たり前じゃないですか
わがままだなあ
Despite my better judgment, I ended up
.joining the Friday Fellows,
我が父の仇である金曜倶楽部の連中と
the guys responsible for the death of our dad, for sukiyaki.
不本意ながらもおいしくすき焼き鍋を囲んでしまった
That night, Benten and I toasted
.the moon at a secret bar.
その夜
私は弁天と秘密の酒場で月に乾杯した
I don't know why, but as she sipped
.from the cocktail in her hand,
そして彼女は
手にした酒を飲みながら
the words "It's sad. It's so sad"
.escaped her lips.
何故か悲しい 悲しいと呟いた
繋いだ手を振りほどけば
You shake off my hand
tsunaida te wo furihodokeba
いたずらに　君微笑む
and idly smile at me
itazura ni kimi hohoemu
春は嵐　ざわざわする
Spring is ripe with the roll of thunder,
haru wa arashi zawazawa suru
もう花びら散りすぼんだ
and some cherry blossoms have already left the branches
mou hanabira chirisubonda
口癖はケセラセラ
Your favorite phrase is "Que será, será"
kuchiguse wa que sera sera
また呟く声がする
I can hear you whisper it again
mata tsubuyaku koe ga suru
彼女はいつもさよなら言わずに
She always vanishes
kanojo wa itsumo
sayonara
without saying "Goodbye,"
iwazu ni
風と消える
just like the wind
kaze to kieru
I don't know what the future will be like,
mirai no koto wa wakaranai keredo
未来のことはわからないけれど
今ここにある奇蹟は僕のものと
but I'll have faith
ima koko ni aru
that little miracles
kiseki wa
are awaiting me
boku no mono to shinjiteru
信じてる
約束なんてしたくないけれど
I don't want to be tied down by promises,
yakusoku nante shitakunai keredo
but let's hold up our hands
sono te wo kazashite
その手をかざして確かなもの
and find something,
tashika na mono
手に入れよう
something permanent
te ni ireyou
それは僕らを輝かす
that will
sore wa
show just who we are
bokura wo kagayakasu
Yodogawa here. Autumn's in
full bloom now, isn't it?
淀川です
すっかり秋ですね
The season brings clear skies
.and a healthy appetite.
天高く食欲の秋
え 真夏？
Huh? It's the middle of summer?
Next Time:
Taking in Fall Colors
そっかあ
That so?